Preliminary Guide to the Central American Solidarity Committee records, 1980 - 1985
Duke University. University Archives
Central American Solidarity Committee records 1980 - 1985
Duke University. Central American Solidarity Committee
0.5 linear feet, Extent: 500 Items
Duke University. University Archives
The Central American Solidarity Committee (CASC) was a student organization chartered at Duke University around 1980. CASC was organized in opposition to U.S. policies and activities regarding Central America, especially military aid to Nicaragua, during the early 1980s. The majority of the records are made up of clippings and event flyers and posters, but the records also include correspondence, publications, petitions, bumper stickers, and other materials produced or collected by the Central American Solidarity Committee. The collection also features materials published and distributed by similar groups, such as the Carolina Interfaith Task Force on Central America, the Durham Action Committee on Central America, and the Committee in Solidarity with the People of El Salvador, Southeast Region. English.
UA.31.08.0003
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Provenance
The Central American Solidarity Committee records was received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1991.
Historical Note
The Central American Solidarity Committee (CASC) was a student organization chartered at Duke University around 1980. CASC was organized in opposition to U.S. policies and activities regarding Central America, especially military aid to Nicaragua and El Salvador, during the early 1980s. The members of CASC organized rallies, demonstrations, educational programs and other events; circulated petitions and mailings; and published literature and articles to raise awareness of the political situation in Central America.
Collection Overview
The majority of the records are made up of clippings and event flyers and posters, but it also includes correspondence, publications, petitions, bumper stickers, and other materials produced or collected by the Central American Solidarity Committee. The collection also features materials published and distributed by similar groups, such as the Carolina Interfaith Task Force on Central America, the Durham Action Committee on Central America, and the Committee in Solidarity with the People of El Salvador, Southeast Region.
Subject Headings
Central America -- Foreign relations -- United States; Civil rights -- El Salvador; Civil rights -- Nicaragua; Committee in Solidarity with the People of El Salvador (U.S.); Duke University. Central American Solidarity Committee; Duke University -- Students -- Political activity; El Salvador -- Politics and government; Nicaragua -- Politics and government; United States -- Foreign relations -- Central America; Bumper stickers; Fliers (printed matter)
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Notebook, ca. 1981-1985 (Box 1)
  - Bumper stickers, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous [events, programs, petitions, flyers], 1981-1985 (Box 1)
  - Writings and publications, 1982-1984 (Box 1)
  - Events, 1981-1984 (Box 1)
  - Posters [and flyers], 1981-1985, undated, [2 folders] (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1985, [2 folders] (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - Literature originals, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Contacts: other groups [rallies, programs of related organizations], 1982-1985, [2 folders] (Box 2)
  - Resources, mass mailings, 1981-1984 (Box 2)
  - People to People, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Posters [activity calendars, pamphlets, clippings], 1981-1985, [2 folders] (Box 2)
  - Carolina Interfaith Task Force on Central America, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Committee in Solidarity with the People of El Salvador (CISPES), Southeast Region, 1982-1984 (Box 2)
  - North Carolina Peace Network, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - Unfoldered material (Box 2)